It’s obvious someone has him killed.
I’ll take care of the Kitti case myself.
Why didn’t you tell me?
You were one of the investigators
on the Thai Investment Bank case.
Are you suggesting Thun is Asura?
Thunwikorn.
His parents got swindled
by the Thai Investment Bank.
They ended their own lives.
This could be his motivation.
His life isn’t all that different from mine.
It has to be something you can guess.
And it must be something
only you and he know.
The ending of Nekros
was just uploaded minutes ago.
The worst thing is…
when law enforcers themselves
are the bad guys.
Your sister came over to visit your uncle
about an hour ago.
If it wasn’t for Nekros,
you’d have found Prim and me as corpses.
There’s a type of murderer
called a mastermind.
He wouldn’t get his hands bloodied.
He borrows someone else’s hands
to do his dirty work.
But don’t worry.
I’ll do anything to prove
that you’re innocent.
So…
What can I do?
Just stay here.
Don’t go anywhere.
I’ll be back soon.
Okay?
Phat…
Will you promise me one thing?
You… will protect the innocent.
And you won’t let anyone
go through what I did.
I promise.
Even if it costs me my life, I’ll do it.
Alright?
Now eat your breakfast.
To all units,
the car approaching belongs to
the commissioner’s relative.
No need to check her identity.
Back to your station.
You haven’t gone to bed, have you, Uncle?
I bought you some swallow nests,
your favorite.
I was afraid you might have gone to bed
so I came here in a rush.
I was just craving it.
You read my mind.
That’s good. I’ll serve it.
It makes me happy
to see you smile again, Praew.
What’s past is past.
You should eat.
It won’t taste good when it’s cold.
Hmm.
Uncle.
I read online that you’re going to be
Nekros’ last victim.
I wouldn’t worry about that nonsense.
I have work to do.
Are you certain about that
because the case happened long ago,
and you thought there was nothing
that would lead to you?
Praew.
What are you saying?
Praew…
I’m sorry. I was just—
It’s alright.
You can keep looking.
There are still so many things
I want you to know, Praew.
Now that you know the whole truth,
how do you think
all this crap should end, Praew?
Okay.
We’ve checked, sir.
The car is a rental.
Contact all checkpoints and tell them
to inspect every suspicious car.
Yes, sir.
What do we have?
I don’t give a damn about some papers!
Look through the playback footage
and look for the car I sent you.
Send me the footage immediately.
I’ll take responsibility for that.
Check every intersection,
and every street that crosses this area.
(Yes, sir.)
(I’m sending you the link
to the real-time footage right now.)
(The suspected car
is heading out of the city, sir.)
What?
Praew?
Why are you doing this?
You should know better than anyone
why I’m doing this.
That journalist is manipulating you.
You’re misunderstanding me, Praew.
No, she isn’t.
The only reason you’re still breathing
is all thanks to your niece.
She asked me to spare you until now
so you can tell her the truth.
Now I’ll let you talk and convince Praew,
however you can,
that you’re really sorry about
all the crap that happened.
And don’t lie.
Because if you do,
there won’t be a second chance.
Praew.
Listen to me.
The truth isn’t what he’s trying
to make you think.
Everything I did was to protect you.
But it wasn’t without a condition.
You need to let this case close.
Forget it. Let it end.
20 YEARS AGO
Don’t dig up anything again.
I’m doing the right thing.
It’s you
who need to stay out of this case.
I won’t bow down to anyone.
I don’t care what big shots they are.
I know them better than you.
If it was just your life on the line,
I wouldn’t get involved.
But they will kill everyone you love
if you don’t stop.
Between your family
and doing what is right,
what is more important to you?
Don’t say I didn’t warn you.
But if I give up now,
what will become of
the hundreds of families out there?
How will you face them
even if you’re alive?
(It’s a shock for the police department)
(when Commissioner Praphaphat Traikanawut
and his wife)
(were killed in a car accident.)
He left behind a scandal
when it’s been revealed that
an important evidence for the infamous
fraud case of Thai Investment Bank
has mysteriously disappeared.
It’s been suspected by the public
that it was Commissioner Praphaphat
who had accepted a bribe
to get rid of the evidence
(which allowed the executives
to walk free.)
(The latest footage we have)
(is of the car taking an exit
out of the main road.)
(There are no traffic cameras
on the side road, sir.)
Send me the latest coordinate.
The truth.
I only want the truth.
Not excuses.
I had to let your father die
to save your and Phat’s lives.
(They were powerful enough
to have your father killed and framed.)
You stood by watching
our father die and take the blame
while you lived on pretending
to be the good guy…
How could you do that?
Did Nop die for your secret, too?
I had to let it happen.
(If I didn’t, your father,
and every victim in that case,)
(would have died for nothing.)
(I had to do this
to make sure I had power.)
(To have enough power to deal with them.)
(Everything has a cost!)
Hello.
Kaye.
Tell me where he is.
(Kaye, please.)
(Just tell me.)
If you don’t stop them right now,
Praew will become a murderer
just like Kim did.
(Kaye, you’re the only one)
who can stop this ending from happening.
Tell me.
And it’s almost time for them
to pay for what they did.
Trust me, Praew.
Praew.
I’ve been hunting them all this time.
But in the end, I learned that
the worst of them
aren't those vile criminals,
but the people who pride themselves
as protectors of laws
who choose to stand with the devil.
No wonder people like us
feel hopeless about justice.
Good.
Today, we will see
what a true monster actually looks like.
Praew, listen to me.
You don’t have to feel guilty
about killing the likes of him.
Just don’t think of them as human beings.
Because what they did
makes them lower than animals.
The guests are going to be here soon,
but it seems we’re not ready.
It’s time to drag him to his end.
Praew, I’ll accept your decision.
If…
If you want me dead,
I won’t refuse.
Why did he want Praew
to send us the video?
It’s a final invitation.
An invitation to the execution
where you and I are the witnesses.
Praew.
Death would be too nice for you.
You have to take responsibility
for what you did.
You have to be branded
a dirty cop like Dad was.
You will die in prison.
You… jerk.
You go this way. I’ll go that way.
Okay. Be careful.
Praew, Praew.
Praew. Praew.
Praew.
Kaye.
Thun… Thun took my uncle.
I got it.
I’m coming with you.
Listen to me, Praew.
Stay here.
Don’t go anywhere.
It’s dangerous.
I’ll handle this.
Took you long enough.
I believed in Praew.
But it’s all ruined now.
But what can we do, huh?
The show must go on.
Am I right?
Enough now.
It’s over now.
And I believe Phat will make things right.
Dai-sensei,
I am the product from the tip of your pen.
You wrote Nekros
because you weren’t brave enough
to make it happen.
I’m just turning your ink… into blood.
Well?
Is the ending you can see
with your own eyes
even more beautiful than
what is on the page?
Get up!
Look.
Look at this geezer!
He’s lived a happy life for 20 years
on the corpses of my parents,
your parents,
and thousands of victims of
the Thai Investment Bank case.
People respect him.
Laws protect him.
Meanwhile, your father was a vegetable
and mine hanged themselves.
Where is justice?
Where is it?
Huh?
Phat.
Just shoot him!
But killing him won’t bring
any of our parents back.
It’s just going to turn us
into monsters like him.
I am no monster, dai-sensei.
I only stain my hands with blood
in order to spread the truth,
the very thing you didn’t
have the guts to do.
And today, the end has come.
What a fun freaking ending it is!
I gotta say this story really
is diverting until the very last act.
Hey, stay still.
Now choose.
In my hand is justice.
In our Inspector’s hand are the laws.
If I throw this lighter,
this scumbag dies.
The world will be lighter.
But if you shoot me, Inspector,
and save him,
all the evidence will be gone by tomorrow.
Choti is dead.
Kitti is also dead.
This jerk will walk free.
And as a wronged hero, at that.
Now why don’t you try and
tell me, Inspector,
that what I just said isn’t true?
What do you think
makes the world go round?
Huh?
You think it’s your stupid justice
that runs this world?
Wrong!
It runs on power!
And I will have that power
beneath my goddamn feet!
But I won’t let you die right now.
I’ll keep you alive as a stepping stone
to a big promotion.
Got it?
Jerk!
Look.
Look what ending waits for someone
who thinks he can beat the system.
Your father was just as stupid.
That’s why he had to die.
As for your family,
and all the scums who died
because of the Thai Investment Bank…
You think that was injustice?
Huh!
No!
It was just the price you had to pay.
You think the world is
beautiful and orderly
because of clean hands?
I sacrificed myself to carry that sin,
stained my hands bloodied,
to build this perfect system,
to build a beautiful world
for you to live in.
You…
My beloved nephew Phat.
If I couldn’t teach you,
I’d rather send you to your father.
K–Kaye…
Kaye
Kaye!
Well?
You gonna let us try and kill each other?
Huh?
Or are we gonna talk nicely
as uncle and nephew again?
No.
I can make this work for us.
We can walk out of here
as heroes together.
We can start over.
It’s beautiful…
Dai-sensei.
Kaye.
I wouldn’t let a good guy
like you lose, Phat.
Kaye!
Thank you for everything
you’ve done for me.
Let me be the monster instead.
Kaye!
There is nothing more shocking
for the nation right now
than the conclusion
to the Nekros serial murder case,
which ended with a tragedy in the fire.
There’s a fire.
Look at the smoke.
Please do not enter.
Oh look. Someone’s injured.
They’re carrying someone out.
(Commissioner Chaiwat, the killer’s
last victim, made it out alive,)
(although with partial burns.)
(But the earth-shattering truth
lies with the revelation that)
(Thun, the sensational journalist,
was the Nekros serial killer,)
(who has been confirmed
to die in the fire.)
(The end has come after 20 years.)
Commissioner Chaiwat Traikanawut
has been arrested
(after a video from Thunwikorn
was revealed.)
(The evidence uncovers that
the Commissioner was responsible)
(for silencing witnesses
and tampering evidence)
(in the Thai Investment case)
(as well as abusing his power
for more than two decades.)
The situation has sent a big ripple
through the public,
making people question the justice system,
and leading to a reform regarding
corruption in the police department.
Alright. You can move the stuff in.
Just place them there.
Uh, excuse me.
Are you here to see someone?
Oh…
Did the previous tenant
take all his stuff?
Actually, the landlord just
had to throw everything out.
I just got a chance to come in
and clean the place up myself.
Right.
Guys, come on.
There are still boxes to unload.
Why not just adopt them?
It’s better this way.
If one day I’m gone,
someone will take care of them.
(This is the last video taken
before his death.)
Hey, you mind turning up the volume?
(The world always asks:)
(How makes a monster?)
LAST CONFESSION FROM THUNWIKORN PUTTHANA
(Is it genetics or a personal decay?)
(But no.)
(A monster is not born on its own.)
(It is born of your ignorance.)
(20 years ago, the national fraud case
led by the Thai Investment Bank)
(robbed my family of everything we had.)
(The people in power leeched off of us)
(and walked away
with spring in their steps.)
(Meanwhile, victims like my parents…)
were cornered by the laws
until their backs were against the wall.
That day, I screamed
at the top of my lungs,
but no one heard me.
Not a single good Samaritan
reached out their hand.
Because they all kept one eye closed
and chose to believe the lie
that the laws could take care of it.
“Let the laws take care of it”?
That day never came.
Then I came across Nekros.
It was a wake-up call for me.
In the end, lies become truths
if the people who know the truth
like you choose to stay silent.
LOAN SHARKS MIX-UP: HOMEOWNER FIGHTS BACK
MAN SHOT AFTER SAVING FRIEND
FROM LOAN SHARKS
(Nekros is simply the scream
you pretend not to hear.)
(My death isn’t the end.)
It’s a question that is forever
ingrained in your brain:
Between a killer who calls for justice
and the unjust system
that kills its victim slowly,
which of these is the actual monster?
PRAPAPHAT TRAIKANAWUT / MEVIKA TRAIKANAWUT
Prim?
Prim.
ONE YEAR LATER
Oh, hey.
Prim is waiting for me. I’m off.
I might be home late tonight.
We’ve got so much work to do.
Umm.
Oh, your favorite manga was just updated.
Bye. See you.
(All this time we ask who the monster is,)
(we forget to ask how to stop
creating another monster.)
(Monsters don’t just hide in the shadows.)
(They also feed on every time
injustice goes unchecked,)
(as we tell ourselves
it’s none of our business.)
(Don’t let anyone fight alone.)
(Because the day people
stop cowering in fears,)
(that is the day change can happen)
(and truth never dies)
(as well as trust,)
(which will find a way to rise again
even as the world burns.)
Kaye?
Is something the matter?
I’m sorry.
I thought you were someone I know.
No problem.
Nekros ended.
What are you going to write now,
Mr. Mangaka?
I don’t know yet.
I don’t even know
if people would read what I write.
Of course they would.
At least I will.
But I’m asking this as a fan,
can’t the next one be something
with a happy ending?
Well then,
I guess you’ll have to
help me write it, Inspector.
Of course.
I’m happy to see you again.
So am I.
THERE IS A POST-CREDIT SCENE.
You have a lighter?